Jenna is a full-stack creative, product designer, and technologist who specializes in the early-stage development of AI-enabled, behavior-changing consumer products.

Works and thinks in Figma, Adobe Creative Cloud, Canva, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Node, Python, data visualization, and design systems.

WORK HISTORY

Freelance Product Designer/Fractional Design Lead @Various Startups 06/2021-Present First/sole design hire for early-stage startups, specializing in 0-to-1 product development.

- Led design processes end-to-end, working cross-functionally with CEOs, product managers, engineers, and subject matter experts to develop new features, launch MVPs, brand refreshes, and app redesigns
- Led design strategy to reconcile user needs with business goals, define product roadmaps, bring founder visions to life, and ultimately boost user activation, retention, and engagement
- Conducted user research and testing to guide product prioritization/design direction
- Worked with engineering to establish design systems, component libraries

Founder/Product @docbotic

06/2021-06/2024

Founded a startup with clinical colleagues from Mindstrong to build the most accessible and effective mental health interventions we could imagine!

- Prototyped and co-designed Sleepbot, the world's first conversational interface to deliver the first-line treatment for insomnia over text messaging
 - In a clinical trial, 50 participants saw a 73% reduction in severe fatigue, and maintained an 80% daily engagement rate, over the 8-week study
 - Led UXR/multiple design iterations based on user interviews, feedback, and usage data from 3000+ users in 130+ countries
- Co-designed a depression intervention over text messaging via clinical partnership with Thomas Jefferson University, currently in clinical trial
- Co-designed an LLM-enhanced burnout intervention over text messaging

Senior Product Designer/Software Engineer, R&D @Mindstrong 11/2020-06/2021

Formed a cross-functional squad of data scientists, clinicians, engineers, and researchers to explore AI applications on clinical tooling for improved workflows, efficacy, and outcomes.

- Led end-to-end design processes, creating artifacts—word docs, design mocks, interactive prototypes and visualizations—for communication, iteration, and testing
- Nurtured a user-centered and clinically-driven product culture by advocating for and integrating clinical voices into the product development process
- Developed 3-week pilot programs for a patient sleep data dashboard

- Worked with clinicians and researchers to make predicted sleep data actionable
- Built interactive dashboards for testing, establishing a cycle of design iteration
- Designed and developed an internal research dashboard
 - Collaborated with data science, clinicians, and the V.P. of Research to determine the clinical utility of passively collected datastreams, turning raw user data into actionable insights directly relevant to clinical workflows

Senior Product Designer @Mindstrong

09/2019-11/2020

- Refreshed Mindstrong's brand identity, working with the V.P. of Marketing to define brand persona, redesign website and create collateral
- Led a redesign of Mindstrong's research-oriented mobile app:
 - Established brand guidelines to inform design system
 - Simplified user flows, interfaces, and information architecture to lower barrier of entry for our Medicaid/Medicare SMI population
 - Created a modular platform for rapid content piloting and iteration
- Helped redesign and develop new features for the clinical web platform:
 - Interviewed our in-house clinicians to identify pain points and opportunities
 - Streamlined the UX/UI to scale for larger caseloads and complex cases
 - Developed new features to facilitate clinical protocols and reduce burnout

Creative Director @Ambassadors for Sustained Health

12/2015-09/2019

- Revamped ASH's digital presence, including a responsive website, new brand identity, integrated brand system, to boost donor engagement
- Conducted user interviews in Kenya to inform user-centered design decisions and develop culturally relevant assets, communications, and service offerings

Digital Designer/Art Director @Various Publishing Houses

09/2012-09/2017

- Transitioned print publications to cross-platform, interactive digital editions
- Developed design systems to streamline multi-platform publishing

EDUCATION

Masters @New York University, Interactive Telecommunications Program

2017-2019

Transdisciplinary graduate program focusing on interaction design, creative applications of new technology, and user-centered design and digital innovation

Bootcamp @Copenhagen Institute of Interaction Design

2017

Bachelors @School of the Art Institute of Chicago

2009-2012

Degree emphasis in visual communication design